<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Dmitry Petrov</title>
 <link href="http://getpoole.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://getpoole.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-07-30T01:53:33+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://getpoole.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Mark Otto</name>
   <email>markdotto@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Out of the Tar Pit</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/28/tar-pit/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/28/tar-pit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Article is rather abstract at start and begins with defining what the accidental and essential complexities are in terms of program systems. The aproach is rather radical, because the essential complexity is treated only as a complexity that directly derives from the user specifications, so all language and infrastructure complexity is accidental which is some sort of bitter true. The proposed approach is to eliminate all possible accidental complexity if possible and separate remaining from so called essential logic and state si that they should not ever know about it&amp;#39;s existance. The proposed way to define such a system is to use relational model which can help defining all the system essential requirements and constraints in a purely declarative manner and just provides endpoints to extend the system with accidental complexity parts if needed for performance or usability reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Station Q</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/25/station-q/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/25/station-q</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is article is related to one of the Microsoft Research project but doesn&amp;#39;t look like ordinary promo page from Microsoft. The purpose of article to clarify the purpose of attempts the Microsoft is doing in the field of quantum computing. What they are trying to do is to develop a scalable method to build quantum computers. Today a lot of labs have an ability to make some kind of quantum computation, but noone can build a stable computer and the reason is that any kind of distraction to one of qubits during computation destroys all the information, and they try to apply a topology to the field to make a protected version of qubit that will be able to resist distraction or at list its distraction will not lead to the failure of the computation. In 2000 a theoretical particle Majorana was proposed to exist and later one of the researches got evidence of their existance. If it&amp;#39;s true it should be more easy to build a protected qubit. It&amp;#39;s just a chance but if it succeeds we will get a scalable way to build quantum computers. Why is it imortant? Theoretically quantum computers are exponentioally more performant than ordinary ones, so the problems that can take thousends of year could take days or even hours and we will see a real explosion of scientific discoveries&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Meet Ray, the self-driving forklift that is parking cars at a German airport</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/25/ray/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/25/ray</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dusseldorf airport adopted the first system for automatic car parking called Ray. Person can just pay for the parking and the robot will lift the car and move it to the parking space. Ray device is fully autonomous and use lasers to navigate. Author claims that with this system the parking can be used up to 40% more efficiently with it than without&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Secret Government Rulebook For Labeling You a Terrorist</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/23/rulebook/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/23/rulebook</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Very detailed article about how US government places people (in us and world-wide) in the lists of the terrorists suspect. Most worries are connected with the fact that the conditions to get in a such list are very wide (the term reasonable suspicion is declared, but it has a very wide definition, a lot of exceptions and if that also does not help, there are exception, that allow to place e person in a list even without any real facts), there is no way for a person to figure out if he is in such a list and there is no public procedure to get out of this list. Moreover existing mechanisms have nothing to do with the official court system and exists inside of military or intelligence agencies without any access from outside. If person was placed in such a list it immediately gets problems with transportation, job and any other area that has something related to security. If we think about other articles that show the scale of monitoring systems developed by US government it becomes really scary and cyberpunk novels become really close to the reality. The last fact that is worth mentioning is that if the person gets in the list all government or government related structures a forced to collect all the possible data of such a person and interestingly it&amp;#39;s not about military and intelligence agencies but also the organizations that should not have any connection with politics and monitoring people like USAID.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Riding the Juggernaut That Left Print Behind</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/21/print/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/21/print</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another article that pokes around the question that print media becomes more the part of the past. It cannot compete with social networks in terms of reaction on events, because new tweets and videos go online almost immediately. The interesting thing that is mentioned by author is that Internet provides different style of reading than print. With internet you just can get enough and always switch to the new content. As a consequence, one can hardly remember the information that he got from all the links he has read today. Probably, it&amp;#39;s not needed, but what is the reason for reading it anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Love People, Not Pleasure</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/21/people-pleasure/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/21/people-pleasure</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Third NYTimes article in a day. This one deals with the question of one&amp;#39;s happiness, no more no less. One statement is that it&amp;#39;s not only happiness and unhappiness, it&amp;#39;s happiness and all shades of unhapiness. Fame, money, sex even make the person more unhappy than he was before, and it&amp;#39;s not the right way to go if the only thing you want to achieve is a happy life. Author states, that all these things work more as adrenaline than a cause for happiness, the more you get it the more you needed the less happy you are. And the only way to avoid this trap is to stop trying to reach happiness though this things.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Letter of Richard Feynman to the graduate</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/21/feynman/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/21/feynman</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The letter Richard Feynman wrote to one of his graduates to explain that it&amp;#39;s worth to work no only with world-scale problems but with all problems that you are capable solving of. If you&amp;#39;re not noticed by most of the world, you&amp;#39;re still known and loved and recognized amongst friends, relatives and colleages and you can always do something about that. Probably it&amp;#39;s worth to print this letter and to hang it on the wall in my room. The stie is worth additional exploration&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Africans Open Fuller Wallets to the Future</title>
   <link href="http://getpoole.com//links/2014/07/21/africa/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://getpoole.com/links/2014/07/21/africa</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Article raises the discussion around current growth of african economies. The country are still mostly poor, but their economies are booming and western companies invest big money not just in mining but also in foods and manufacturing. Also the number of people with middle income raises and they are not the only one close to the ruling party. South Africa still performs the best, but Nigeria also shows rapid growth. They even launched several satellites which is almost unique amongst african countries. In the next century the whole region can become a driver of growth of the world. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
